<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-04-15T00:09:12+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Welcome to my blog</title><subtitle>This blog will mainly deal with robust Machine Learning and thoughts about financial history and present</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The benefit of having several projects at once</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/04/15/benefit-of-having-several-projects.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The benefit of having several projects at once" /><published>2022-04-15T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/04/15/benefit-of-having-several-projects</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/04/15/benefit-of-having-several-projects.html">&lt;p&gt;I recently had an argument with a colleague about doing a side-project next to my main project.
Our two positions were mainly that a side-project can give valuable experience and inspiration vs. 
that  a side-project might be too distracting from the main project that this colleague currently focused on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I do believe that focus is essential for performing good work,
I also believe that it can be difficult and even risky to spend at least half a year
full-time on only one small project. While the focusing on one project can for sure help the progress on this one project,
chances are that one looses practice in thinking about different things and solving novel problems from scratch. This process
of diving deep into a new or slightly different topic usually has a huge learning increase in the beginning, that can be useful
later on in the main project and for sure helps to keep one in-state to roll out an end-to-end problem solving algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, I think no matter what you do, the most important thing is that you like what you do and that you keep your learning
curve as steep as possible, with whatever method you like to do that. In the long-run, this system will likely benefit you a lot 
when you accumulate more and more knowledge and skills that you can apply on whatever project you are working on in the future.
If a side-project that you are interested in and that promises to be fun happens to come with a steep-learning curve, even better.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="motivation" /><category term="improving" /><summary type="html">I recently had an argument with a colleague about doing a side-project next to my main project. Our two positions were mainly that a side-project can give valuable experience and inspiration vs. that a side-project might be too distracting from the main project that this colleague currently focused on.</summary></entry></feed>